retouchpro.com 2011-05-26

# RetouchPRO Privacy Statement & Terms of Use

Privacy Statement & Terms of Use

**Terms of Use**

Please read this notice before using our site. By using the site, you agree to abide by these Terms of Use; please do not use our site if you do not agree with the Terms of Use outlined below. RetouchPRO reserves the right to modify the Terms of Use at its sole discretion, and by using this site, you agree to be bound by the modifications or updates to the Terms of Use. 

**Privacy Notice**

RetouchPRO values your privacy. To keep you informed, we have created this privacy statement that discloses our purposes and methods for online collection and use of information. This statement applies to all information collected through the RetouchPRO.com website and information gathered from any web pages that we host. 

**Types of Information Collected**

Generally, personal information is not collected from visitors to the RetouchPRO website. However, in order to access certain special services, personal information is requested; those cases are described in more detail below. 

**Bulletin Board Registration**

RetouchPRO requires a valid e-mail address for users who want to participate in the RetouchPRO Discussion Forums. This allows us to protect our community from abusive postings and provides a verifiable point of contact should legal questions arise. At any time, you have the ability to keep your e-mail address hidden from other users by selecting that option within your user profile. 

Also in the forum registration, you have the option of providing some additional information such as occupation, interests, and homepage URL. This information is made available to other bulletin board users to foster a sense of community. If you have any concerns about providing this information, simply leave the fields blank and your registration will still be processed. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

Certain activities on the RetouchPRO website involve the use of "cookies" to facilitate your experience. This includes retention of your username and password for the RetouchPRO forums and showing a default Topic View when you visit the forums. You have the option to turn these cookies off at any time by updating your user profile preferences. If your browser doesn’t support cookies, or if you have cookies turned off, these preferences will not be set.

We also use third party advertisements on the RetouchPRO website to support our site.  Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.  This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York retailer ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security.  However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites.  This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts. 

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. 
  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to you based on your visit to this site and other sites on the Internet. 
  * You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

**Log Files**

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files.  The information in the log files include  your IP (internet protocal) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

RetouchPRO does not disclose your personally identifying information to any third parties for any purpose without your prior consent. All reasonable care is taken to ensure its security both offline and online. 

It’s also important to be aware that when you voluntarily provide personal information (e.g., address, phone number) in a posting on the bulletin board, that information is publicly available and may be used by someone in a manner unintended by you. For that reason, we encourage using caution before offering of any personally identifying information within the message board itself. 

**Changing or Updating Personal Information**

You can update or change your user profile on RetouchPRO by clicking on the "User CP" option on the Forums page. 

If you have questions regarding your information, you can contact our Administrator [here](http://www.retouchpro.com/forums/sendmessage.php).
